## **ABOUT ME**

Researcher and data analyst with background in applied occupational and industry research as well as demographic public policy analytics. Passionate about using data to deepen understanding of the interplay of economic, ecological, and community systems in cities and regions. Experienced in the use of various analytics methods and interested in further developing both technical aptitude and subject matter knowledge about community development and related topics. Open to Nashville based or remote work opportunities.

#### CONTACT

mccalljoanna@gmail.com

615-772-7365

Nashville, TN

LinkedIn

**GitHub** 

Tableau Public

# RELEVANT SKILLS

**Excel (Power Pivot)** 

Tableau

PowerBI

SQL (PostgreSQL)

Python (Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Geopandas)

Jupyter Notebooks

**Public Speaking** 

**Project Management** 

**Qualtrics & Survey Methods** 

Agile & Kanban

**ArcGIS Software** 

**Map Production** 

### **EXPERIENCE**

Nashville Software School, Nashville TN | January 2021 - Present

**Data Analytics Apprentice** 

The NSS Data Analytics school is an intensive five month program covering skills in advanced Excel, PostgreSQL, PowerBI, Tableau, GitHub, Python, and Agile processes. This program focuses on using real-time data to create analyses that mirror current needs of analytics employers.

- Short Term Rentals in Nashville Council Districts | Geospatial analysis of short term rentals in Nashville. Examines where investment from outside the State, city, and respective zip code is prevalent. Technologies used: GeoPandas, Folium.
- <u>Energy Consumption, Generation, and Access Over Time</u> | Tableau visualization of global electricity access, energy consumption, and energy generation over multiple decades. Energy consumption and generation is broken out twice: by high level sources including renewables, nuclear, and fossil fuels, as well as popular renewable modes including wind and solar.
- GDP and Internet Access | Gained insights about the relationship between internet use and GDP from 2004 to 2014. Technologies used: Pandas, Jupyter Notebooks.

Nashville Area Chamber of Commerce, Nashville TN | November 2018 - December 2020 Research Coordinator and Analyst

The Research Center at the Nashville Chamber acts as data and analytics resource internally, to business members of the organization, and to the regional community. Expertise areas include economic, workforce, and community development.

- 2020 Music Industry Report | Report providing market research on the music industry leading up to and during COVID-19. Led a team conducting over 100 stakeholder interviews, multiple focus groups, and distributed surveys retrieving real-time workforce information receiving over 2,500 responses. In order to determine the economic impact of music related business activity for benchmarking, staffing matrices were utilized to determine areas of employment that are not captured in many impact reports such as music venue employment.
- 2020 Workforce Study | Study identifying opportunity pathways to connect workers in the Middle Tennessee region to training, credentials, and degrees. The work, done in conjunction with the Northern Middle Tennessee Local Workforce Development Board, provides groundwork for collaboration among policy makers, educators, talent and economic development professionals, employers and researchers.
- Vital Signs 2019 | This report provides regional indicators pertaining to the economy, the workforce, and the community. In 2019 I assisted with distribution and data cleaning for a regional survey of residents receiving over 4,000 responses.
- <u>Data Visualizations</u> | Utilized Census Bureau, Bureau of Labor Statistics, and Vital Signs 2019 Survey data to create Tableau dashboards bringing in-house data visualization capacity to the Research Center.

Environmental Law & Policy Center, Chicago IL | January - June 2018 Policy Intern

ELPC is the leading environmental advocacy organization in the Midwest United States.

- School Bus Electrification | Research and advocacy supporting school bus electirfication in 9 Midwestern states related to Volkswagen settlement funds. This work consisted of research on the impact of other funding proposals, notable funding of passenger rail modernization. Ultimately, 10% of funding was allocated for electric school buses.
- Solar Capacity Mapping | Tracking and mapping of state-wide solar speculation related to the Future Renewable Energy Jobs Act. I was
  responsible for monitoring and categorizing various publications for reports of prospective solar projects related to developing policy in
  order to garner understand the overall patterns of location type, capacity, and concentration of speculation so that the oganization was
  able to develop comments and position on the policy.

Cut Cats Courier Collective, Chicago IL | 2014 - 2018

**Co-Owner and Operator** 

CCC specializes in bicycle delivery for contracted clients and is the largest service collective in the Midwest.

- · Client Relationships | Built and maintained client relationships.
- Navigation, Routing, Delivery | Rapid navigation and delivery via bicycle.

## **EDUCATION**

Nashville Software School | Expected Graduation May 2021 Full - Time Data Analytics Bootcamp

DePaul University | Graduated June 2018
Masters in Sustainable Urban Development
Specialization: Renewable Energy Research & Advocacy, GIS
Chaddick Scholar: Chaddick Institute for Metropolitan Development
GPA 3.8/4.0

DePaul University | Graduated June 2016 Bachelors in Physics, Interdisciplinary Concentration in Studio Art Graduated Cum Laude GPA 3.90/4.0

# **COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT**

Council Member, Healthy Nashville Leadership Council 2018 - 2020

Served on council responsible for drawing attention to important public health problems and encouraging community-wide action through development of iterations of the Metro-Nashville Community Health Improvement Plan.

Transit Citizen's Leadership Academy
The Transit Alliance of Middle Tennessee
Spring 2019

Course provides education about multimodal transit and the necessity of various transit options in the Middle Tennessee region.